

Software Developer seeking roles in Software Development, Application
Programming, Requirement Gathering, Agile Methodology, System Integration, Client
Management, Risk Management, Spring Framework, Eclipse, Javascript, Core
Java, Spring Boot, Hibernate



Current Designation: Software Developer Total Experience: 2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Shell Infotech Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Davangere, Mysore Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Requirement Gathering, Agile Methodology, System Integration, Client Management, Risk Management, Spring Framework, Eclipse, Javascript, Core

Java, Spring Boot, Hibernate

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

Development used spring MVC, Hibernate, Web Services (Rest).

Token generation.

Worked with Spring Boot Implementations.

Developed PDF using I-Text and PDFBox APIs both in English and Arabic

Internalization.

Developed interactable PDF.

Marshaling and un-marshaling of xml files.

Done Junit testing.

Business Integration testing.

Efficiently performed different roles.

Have good knowledge of quality process & Issue Tracking.

Resolved Level 1 or Level 2 tickets to the onsite team when application

goes down and follow up the team till the issue gets resolved.

Assigning and solving issues through tickets according to the severity using Jira.

Application Developer having work experience in building software applications using Devops.

worked with develops tools such CA Agile, Git, Maven, Jira, SVN.

Familiar with Apache MQ and JMS Server

Work Experience

Shell Infotech as Software Developer Jun 2020 to Till Date

Project/Team Qspace Client Internal Project Duration July 2020 - present

Main Technologies Used

Core Java, JavaScript, Spring MVC, Hibernate, Postgres 11, Spring

Boot, Restful Webservices & Tomcat Server

DESCRIPTION

QSpace enables clients to digitize the end-to-end validation process for IT systems. This rapidly deployable cloud-based platform integrates a number of aspects of IT quality and compliance within a single risk-based platform. QSpace uses lean processes and system-induced controls to help reduce human errors and create enterprise-wide collaboration opportunities.

Experis IT Pvt. Ltd as Software Developer

Feb 2019 to Jun 2020

Project/Team E11(Edirham)
Client: Ministry of Finance, Dubai.
Duration Feb 2019 to June 2020
Main Technologies Used
Core Java, JavaScript, Spring MVC, Hibernate, Oracle 10g, Spring
Boot, Restful Webservices & JBoss Server

DESCRIPTION

The e-Dirham is a payment tool introduced by the government of the Unite d Arab Emirates with the aim of facilitating the collection of revenues of gov ernmental and non-governmental service fees in a safe and secure way. The e-Dirham has become widely available and has many payment channels. The Ministry of Finance and Industry has worked and is still working on expanding payment channels. Currently available payment channels include.

Education

UG: B.Sc (Computers) from Bangalore University, Bangalore in 2014

PG: MCA (Computers) from Visveswaraiah Technological University (VTU) in 2018

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Core Java [Java 8], Advance java			
JavaScript			
SPRING FRAMEWORK			
spring boot			
RESTful Web Services			
Hibernate			
JPA			
JDBC			
SQL			
JUNIT			
Log 4j			
JAXB			
JSP			
text / PDFBox			
GIT			
SVN			
MAVEN			
Jenkins			

1/22/2021 $https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=56e5265d4d609eb8564017774dcea89a5e5c5d5219135f14514446590\dots\\$

JIRA	
MicroServices	
MAIL API	
JMS [Active MQ]	
ORACLE 11G	
Postgres 11	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Telugu				
Kannada				

Affirmative Action

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time